Sandeep Saini

Professional Title

Sr Analyst Critical thinker with 5+ years of experience in Strategic Consulting & Project Management Extensive experience in supporting and developing content and analytics driven marketing solutions for CPG/FMCG/Banking/Retail/Pharma/Hotel Industry, etc. domains.. Experience in forecasting, Customer segmentation, marketing measurements, Experience in explanatory data analysis for operational performance reporting.

xaini91sandeep@gmail.com

9998064714

BharatGarh, District - RupNagar, Punjab Pin - 140114, Rupnagar, India

in linkedin.com/in/sandeep-saini-83989b179

twitter.com/Sandeep88877444? t=qYyomw8Hmmu0jkviy9-zSg&s=03 facebook.com/saini.sandeep3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Administrator(Sr. Data Analyst) Numerator

05/2017 - Present Vadodara

Data with advanced technology to create unique insights for the market research

- Consulting and Analytics: Analyzing 360 degree media spend data to provide insightful reporting and analytics to drive competitive advantage and recommendation to optimize client's promo efficiency. Overseeing a sub-team to ensure quality and maintain KPI.
- Focus on establishing and ensuring adherence to an enterprise data governance framework for data policies, standards and best practices, both at the department, Business and functional areas level to achieve the required level of consistency, quality and protection to meet overall business needs.
- Develop and support reporting process, and act as subject matter expert and analyze production reports which helps operations to work smoother and improves process.
- Access intelligence that allows clients to monitor the entire campaign lifecycle and make them understand their share of voice, so they can invest the budgets where they'll make the biggest difference and prove the value of their media spend.
- Collaborating with Data Management team to assist in resolving data quality problems and become a key driver of process improvement and efficiencies for data management. Perform Data analysis
- Interacting with customers to understand their ask and documenting their requirements, Ad hoc reporting - Prepare Reports and Dashboard using data visualization tools (Power BI) to analyze historical data.
- Client Deliverables Work on Daily, weekly, Monthly and Quarterly reports and delivering them in a timely manner.

Jr. Data Administrator

Numerator

05/2017 - Present

Content Analyst TAM Media

12/2016 - 05/2017

 Create print and digital content for companies that provides information or showcases the products or services they offer and to develop content that accurately reflects company ideals, often research the material they need to write each article or product description.

EDUCATION

Maharaja Sayaji Rao University Bsc (Statistics)

SKILLS



LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Punjabi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Gujarati

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Chess Videography Acting

NGO

06/2009 - 10/2012